# Darko Jovanovski

### Senior iOS Developer

I have worked as a Software Engineer for over 4 years now, my primary focus is iOS Development. I am Enthusiastic and determined to achieve set goals. Organized and devoted with a flair for prioritizing. An avid learner with a wide range of different skills and abilities. Can easily adapt to various types of working environments. Capable of working in teams and individually.



∠ djovanovski.dev@gmail.com

+38975389298

Skopje, Macedonia

djovanovski.github.io

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior iOS Developer - Contractor Wacom Europe GmbH

05/2018 - Present

Sofia, Bulgaria

Achievements/Tasks

- Contractor position, help onsite team to redesign and rewrite 2 applications from Objective - C to Swift
- Designing and building advanced applications for the iOS platform
- Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features

### Senior iOS Developer MusalaSoft

09/2018 - Present

Sofia, Bulgaria

Achievements/Tasks

- Work closely with product management & UX to execute an idea from concept to delivery using excellent software design, coding, & processes
- Sprint Planning, task breakdowns and delegating tasks to other team members
- Code reviews
- Simultaneously manage multiple projects and meet many strict deadlines

# iOS Developer

# MusalaSoft

05/2017 - 08/2018

Sofia, Bulgaria

Achievements/Tasks

- Design and build advanced app features for the iOS platform
- Ensure the performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications
- Communicate with a team of developers, designers, project managers, and other personnel to ship new features
- Working with the biggest Telecommunications companies in Bulgaria with high active number of users using the iOS Applications

### SKILLS & COMPETENCES

Communication

Innovative

Teamwork

Problem solving

Mentoring

Project management

## **PROJECTS**

#### Bamboo Paper 🗹

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/bamboopaper/id443131313?mt=8

### Inkspace 🗹

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wacom-inkspaceapp/id1029007767?mt=8

#### MyTelenor Bulgaria 🗗

https://itunes.apple.com/bg/app/mytelenorbulgaria/id1186781645?mt=8

#### My A1 🗹

https://itunes.apple.com/bg/app/my-a1/id1104333674?mt=8

#### Vivacom TV GO 🗹

https://itunes.apple.com/bg/app/vivacom-tvgo/id981422931?mt=8

#### Upshift 🗹

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/upshift/id1211135806? mt=8

#### TopYa! Soccer 🗹

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/topya-soccer/id888381678? mt=8

### Ало Кафана - Alo Kafana 🗹

 https://itunes.apple.com/mk/app/алокафана/id1337848157?mt=8

### Worddio: Vocabulary builder (01/2018 - 05/2018) $\Box$

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/worddio-learn-newwords/id1012362082?mt=8

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### iOS Developer

**ITCrowd** 

08/2016 - 04/2017

Skopje, Macedonia

Achievements/Tasks

- Client communication throughout project development
- Working in a team
- Mentoring interns and junior devs
- Worked onvariety of Swift & Objective-c projects

# Junior iOS Developer

**GSIX Solutions** 

06/2015 - 07/2017

Skopje, Macedonia

Achievements/Tasks

- Interacting with senior developers and business teams and develop features that enhance the software
- Working with technical support team and quality control specialists to create new iOS features and troubleshoot customer problems and fix bugs
- Understand, debug, and improve existing code

## iOS Developer, Internship

IT.MK

12/2015 - 05/2016

Skopje, Macedonia

Achievements/Tasks

- Reading books about iOS Development
- Creating POC(Proof of concept) applications
- Help fixing small bugs

# **EDUCATION**

# Faculty of computer science and engineering - FINKI

Saints Cyril and Methodius University of Skopje

09/2012 - 09/2017

Skopje, Macedonia

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

iOS Advanced Course (09/2014 - 11/2014)

Seavus Education Center

iOS Basic Course (05/2014 - 08/2014)

Seavus Education Center

Cisco CCNA2 (01/2014 - 05/2014)

Cisco Networking Academy

CISCO CCNA1 (09/2013 - 12/2013)

Cisco Networking Academy

## **LANGUAGES**

Macedonian				
English				0
Bulgarian				0
German		0	0	0

### **INTERESTS**

